Tejas Borde

🕥 github.com/tejasborde </br>

 tejasborde.com
 linkedin.com/in/tejasborde
 tejasborde99@gmail.com

Summary

A skilled software developer with expertise in Java, Python, C/C++, NodeJS, ReactJS, and Spring Boot. Holds a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with a remarkable GPA of 9.9/10. Contributed to various projects, including the integration of malware scanning functionality into VMware backup flows and the development of an API Testing Framework. Achievements include leading teams in building assessment frameworks for programming proficiency evaluation and developing Full Stack web applications for diverse tasks. Continuing to drive innovation as an Software Developer.

EDUCATION

Pimpri Chinchwad College of Engineering, Pune (Savitribai Phule Pune University)

June 2023

B.E. Computer Science

GPA: 9.9/10

Courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures & Algorithms, Machine Learning, Operating System, Cloud Computing, Relational & Non-Relational Databases

SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, C/C++, JavaScript Frameworks: NodeJs, ReactJs, Spring Boot, Flask

Database: Postgresql, MySql, MongoDB

Cloud: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services (EC2), Docker, Kubernetes, Salesforce, Informatica Cloud Tools: Git/GitHub/Gitlab, BitBucket, Unix Shell, Mobaxterm, Putty, VS Code, IntelliJ/PyCharm

EXPERIENCE

Veritas Technologies, Pune | Associate Software Engineer

July, 2023 – Present

As a member of the BAAS (Backup as a Service) team, I actively contributed to developing robust protection services, enhancing granular file restore capabilities, implementing a comprehensive API testing framework & reliable database upgrade testing framework.

Veritas Technologies, Pune | Associate Software Engineer Intern

January, 2023 – June, 2023

During my internship, I contributed to a project by developing C/C++ code to integrate a malware scanner into the existing backup workflow for VMware workloads. I also worked on performing malware scans on backup copies before restoration, achieved by mounting the backup copies to files and folders.

Syngenta Services Pvt. Ltd., Pune | Software Engineer Intern

August, 2022 – December, 2022

As a Software Engineer Intern, I focused on utilizing Informatica Cloud to efficiently transform data stored across various sources including SQL databases, Salesforce, etc., streamlining data integration processes for enhanced organizational efficiency.

KPIT Technologies Ltd., Pune | Software Developer Intern

 $July,\ 2021-March,\ 2022$

As a software developer intern, I led a team of four individuals in utilizing ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, GitLab APIs, and their CI/CD features to build a robust assessment framework for evaluating trainees' proficiency in programming languages like C, C++, and Embedded C.

PROJECTS

Database Upgrade Test Framework | Java, Docker, TestContainers

- Developed a Java-based framework for testing SQL changelogs..
- The framework is utilized by the wider team to ensure changelogs are compatible for upgrades.
- Integrated the framework with an in-house build-test engine to validate SQL changelogs before PR merge.

API Testing Framework | Spring Boot, Spring Boot Tests, RabbitMQ, PostgreSql, TestContainers

- Developed an API Testing Framework using Spring Boot Test, Rest Assured, and TestContainers Library.
- Created a mocking framework to simulate RabbitMQ responses from other services.

Malware Scan $\mid C/C++$

- Integrated malware scanning functionality into the existing backup flow for VMware workloads.
- Implemented termination of the backup process if the Virtual Machine Disk (VMDK) of the VMware workload is detected to be infected with malware.

Radyance (Web App) | NodeJs, ReactJs, MongoDB, Razorpay Api, AWS EC2, Linux, NGNIX

- Developed a Full Stack Application using JavaScript frameworks such as ReactJs, NodeJs for affiliate marketing.
- It involves user registration/login, referral scheme, listing user's income on dashboard, payout, etc
- Developed admin side for maintenance of courses, users, payouts and their related details.

Skill Evaluation Portal (Web App) | NodeJs, ReactJs, MongoDB, Linux, NGNIX, Gitlab Api's

- Developed a Full Stack web Application using JavaScript frameworks such as ReactJs, NodeJs & MongoDB, Gitlab CI/CD features to take assessments of newly hired trainees in C/C++/Embedded C .
- It involves user registration, Gitlab SSO login, Test Scheduling, Score Calculation, Reporting, etc

Bulk Emailer (Web App) | NodeJs, ReactJs, MongoDB, Linux, NGNIX, Gitlab Api's

- Developed an application using ReactJs, NodeJs, MongoDB, Nodemailer library to schedule and send emails to multiple recipents at same time.
- It involves features such as sending Banners, HTML message, attachments, etc

Discord Bot | Python, discord.py, Repl.it

- Developed a discord bot in python using discord python sdk to list down live cricket matches and their scores.
- Cricket scores were made available using open source api hosted on rapidapi.com

To-Do-List App | Flask-Python, Jinja, SqlAlchemy, Heroku

- Developed a to-do-list application using flask server and sqlite db.
- Developed app was hosted on heroku using its free offering.

Hobbies

In my free time, I enjoy indulging in various hobbies such as playing cricket and football, listening to music, and embarking on adventurous trips traveling on my bike. These activities allow me to unwind, stay active, and explore new places, contributing to a balanced lifestyle outside of work.